In the previous lesson,
在上一节课中
we've learned how to write our code in functions,
我们学习了将代码写成函数的方法
mostly to organize our code into blocks that can be used in other places in our program.
总的来说 就是把代码组织成模块 以便在程序的其它位置使用
This is very helpful when we want to use this function many times,
如果我们想多次使用函数的话 这么做的好处就凸显出来了
because instead of rewriting all that code over here,
因为那样我们就不用重头写一遍这些代码了
we can just call that function multiple times whenever needed.
只需在必要时调用函数就可以了 而且函数还能调用多次
Say for example, you and a few of your friends were asked to program
打个比方 你和几个朋友收到任务
this alarm clock so that when it's time for the alarm to go off say at 6:00 am,
要给这个闹钟编程 让它到了该响的时候 比如说到了早上六点就响
it should continue to beep forever until someone hits the snooze button.
它会一直响 直到有人按下打盹按钮
Some of your teammates have already created and implemented some functions for you.
已经有几个队友帮你创建并实现了一些函数
One function is called beep,
其中一个函数叫做 beep (铃声)
which when called causes the alarm speakers to emit a single beeping sound.
调用该函数时 闹钟喇叭就会发出一次哔声
Another function is called checkAlarm,
另一个函数叫 checkAlarm (响铃检查)
that returns a boolean,
调用时会返回一个布尔值
which is true if the alarm is on or false if the alarm is off,
如果闹钟响着 值为真 如果闹钟没有响 则值为假
which basically means someone hit the snooze button.
闹钟不响的话 也就意味着有人按下了打盹按钮
You're supposed to create a third function called alarm.
而你的任务是创建第三个函数 叫 alarm (响铃)
This function will be called when it's time for the alarm to go off.
一旦到闹钟该响的时候 这个函数就会被调用
Your alarm function here should basically continue to repeatedly
基本上 这个 alarm 函数得持续不断地调用 beep 函数
call this beep function for as long as this checkAlarm function returns true.
除非 checkAlarm 函数返回的结果不为真
So, to implement your alarm function,
所以 要实现 alarm 函数
you need to call those two functions inside.
你需要在这个函数里调用另外两个函数
Our alarm function doesn't return anything,
我们的 alarm 函数不会返回任何事物
so it's public void alarm.
所以得写 public void alarm
It also doesn't have any input parameters so it's just empty brackets there.
该函数也没有任何输入参数 所以让这里的括号空着就好
First thing we need to do is check if the alarm is on.
首先 我们需要检查闹钟是否响着
We just do this by calling
要做到这一点 只需调用 checkAlarm 函数
the checkAlarm function and store that into a boolean called on here.
并将其储存到这个叫 on 的布尔值里
The next thing we want to do is check if this on variable
接下来我们要判断这个变量 on
or the return of the checkAlarm function is true.
也就是 checkAlarm 函数的返回值是否为真
In that case we want to call the beep function.
如果为真 我们就需要调用 beep 函数
So, we do this using an if block.
为此我们需要使用 if 模块
We say if on and then just beep.
写 if (on) 然后是 beep
This would basically call the beep function emitting a beep noise,
这么写 如果闹钟响着
if the alarm is on.
就会调用 beep 函数 使闹钟发出一声哔了
If it has been turned off then we just skip this beep and nothing happens.
如果闹钟被关了 我们就直接跳过 beep 函数 什么都不会发生
However, we want to keep repeating this beep sound.
然而 我们想让哔声不断地响
So, the first thing we need to do next is to check the alarm again,
所以接下来 我们得再次检查闹钟
and see if it returns true or false and update the on variable.
看看 checkAlarm 的返回结果是真还是假 然后更新变量 on
So, we say on equals checkAlarm again.
所以我们再写一次 on = checkAlarm
After that, we need to check if on is true again.
之后 我们得再判断一次 on 是否为真
So, we do another if block check if on is true,
所以再写个 if 模块 如果判断出 on 为真
then do another beep and update the on with another checkAlarm call.
就再次调用 beep 函数 然后再调用 checkAlarm 函数 更新变量 on
Remember that checkAlarm is the only way we can
记住 要判断是否有人关掉了闹钟
tell if someone has turned off the alarm or hit the snooze button.
或是按下了打盹按钮 我们只能使用 checkAlarm 函数
So, we have to keep calling checkAlarm after every beep,
因此 每次响铃后 我们都得调用 checkAlarm 函数
just to check if someone has turned the alarm off.
检查是否有人关了闹钟
And then every time after that,
每次检查后
we need to add another if block to emit
我们需要再添加一个 if 模块
another beep sound and then check again, and so on.
使闹钟再发出一声哔 然后再检查 不断循环往复
When will this ever end?
那这什么时候能到头啊？
How many times should I repeat this if block here?
我得重复这个 if 模块多少次呢？
What if no one turns off the alarm for a while?
如果短时间内都没人关掉闹钟呢？
Can you think of the number of times I need to repeat this if block here?
你能想想我得重复这个 if 模块多少次吗？
Remember that the purpose of this function is to continue beeping until
记住 这个函数是要让闹钟一直响铃
someone turns the alarm off even if it has to beep forever.
直到有人关了闹钟 否则的话 它会永远响着